I covered Glinax several years ago. In
fact, when Physionic was a wee brand,
unbeknownst to most of you, and this one
video that I did blew up. Anyway, at the
time, there was some incredibly
compelling evidence for GLEAC
supplementation, otherwise known as
glycine and an acetylcyine, hitherto
unto thee, called Glinac Masher.
But that was a few years ago. And what
is the evidence now? Is Gleax still a
great recommendation? Why is it a waste
of money for a lot of people? Well,
we'll get into that. Now, this video is
sponsored by the Physionic Insiders, but
more on them later. We both know you're
going to skip through that ad later,
too, but let's smile and pretend. So,
GLYAC again, that's a dual combination
of the amino acid glycine plus the
molecule N acetylcyine took the health
supplement world by storm when studies
began emerging on its incredible
potential. For example, in mice, glyc
extended lifespan. All you need to know
is that if the lines extend further to
the right, they live longer. So, ooh, we
clearly see the green line. The Gleak
group lived much longer. Now, the
proposed reason for this life extension
potential, and don't worry, we'll get
into some human evidence shortly, is due
to the potent ability for glyc
facilitate the production of a master
antioxidant in our cells called
glutathione.
This antioxidant, glutathione, is a
tripeptide, meaning it's made of three
amino acids. And guess what two of them
are? You're sharp as a hammer. Glycine
and cyine. The reason that we focus on
these two is because the third one is
not rate limiting. Now, I'm going to
swerve the biochemistry here and just
say that we don't need to supplement
with it. So, glutathione is potent in
that it interacts with damaging
molecules produced in our body called
free radicals like reactive oxygen
species that interact with components of
our cells and damage them. So, naturally
neutralizing them would be a net
benefit. That's where glutathione
sacrifices itself to protect your
inards. We'll return to this because
it's important to understand why many
people should not supplement with glo.
For now, we should be asking, well,
fine. But do we have any evidence that
glyc works through glutathione? In
short, yes, as seen across three
different tissues. This is three
different versions of glutathione. We're
looking at total, reduced, and oxidized.
That means that the total amount, if
that's reduced or oxidized. The reduced
is the version that is capable of acting
as an antioxidant. And the oxidized is
the spent glutathione, like a spent
shell casing. Naturally, we want total
and reduced to be high, so higher bars.
And we don't really care about the
oxidized spent glutathione. But I'll go
ahead and mention that nothing changes
on that front anyway. So let's forget
about it. The blue bars are the young
and the red are the old and the green
are the glyax supplemented. We're seeing
across multiple tissues, heart, liver,
kidney that glutathione is significantly
increased with gleac supplementation.
Now they really had to wrestle these
people down and tie them down before
removing their organs.
And three, two, one. I kid, this was a
mice. Still not wonderful, but
scientists don't abduct people and
experiment on them. At least not the
ones that I know. The main point from
all this is to say that in animals we
can extend lifespan drastically and we
believe that it could be through huge
rebounds in glutathione. Though
technically we need more experiments to
really make that last statement
absolute. Now, while you are cute,
you don't look like a rodent to me.
Though the story gets far more [snorts]
interesting when we bring in studies
that are done on people. Now if you were
to have a group of people supplementing
on a placebo substance i.e. not gleac
and have another group of people
supplement with glyc what happens? Do we
see similar results like what we did in
our squeakier subjects? Well, look for
yourself. We're measuring glutathione in
muscle transformed here for your viewing
pleasure. In red, we have the glyax
supplementing group and in gray, the
placebo. The higher the bars go, the
more glutathione is in the tissue. We're
measuring at baseline two weeks later
and 16 weeks later. Now, it's obvious
that muscle glutathione is hugely
increased with supplementation, the same
results as in mice. And I'll mention too
that other measures also indicate this
to be true in other accessible areas
like red blood cells. And when looking
at the direct impact as in the
improvements in the number of these
oxidizing molecules, remember that's the
reactive oxygen species, we see huge
declines. So while the placebo group is
being bombarded by multiplefold more of
these damaging molecules, the gllinac
condition gets a significant reprieve.
Now I'll be returning to this later too
because I'm actually being a little
deceptive with the data that I'm
presenting to you right now. But hang
tight. I'll turn myself in soon. These
kinds of results are also seen in other
measures like inflammation. The point
here being that we have parody between
the animal data and the human data as it
relates to cellular effects of glyc
supplementation. Now in truth though
most supplement research tends to focus
on these kinds of outcomes. What's
happening on a biochemical a cellular
and maybe on features of disease like
blood pressure. But few measures
actually measure function as in does
your body function better. A common
measure of bodily function and frailty
is something called gate speed test
which assesses the speed at which you
walk translating to improved power
coordination and more. Well, across
multiple measures of physical function
like the gate test, but also grip
strength, chair rise tests, Klein
provided remarkable improvements in just
16 weeks. Now, there's plenty of other
measures, but the bottom line is that
GLINE doesn't just help a bit in obscure
cellular measures, but in direct
dayto-day scenarios as well. Now, I
mentioned a bit of deception on my part.
And what I meant is that the research
that we've been looking at is in older
individuals, people in their 70s, and
I've been keeping the data in younger
individuals in their 20s out. So all the
positive results that we've covered up
to now have been in older individuals,
but here's an example of the data
including the youngans. Now we're
looking at glutathione levels again.
This is the same striking data as
before, but I've added the complete data
set including the young in blue there on
the left. The reason I'm bringing this
up is not because it diminishes our
impressions of Glac. It actually further
impresses. We're seeing here that people
50 years older who take GLAC are able to
achieve glutathione levels similar to
people five decades younger. And I'll
let you in on another little not so
secret. This wasn't the only time that
they had similar data. Across many
measures, older individuals
supplementing Gleak had massive
improvements similar to young. Now to
rain it in a bit, it was not universal.
Some measures were improved, but not
quite to the same level of younger
participants. But keep these data in
mind because they tell us another
critical clue that I'll get into in just
a minute. Now, there's much more that
Glac does. So, if you're interested in
mitochondrial health, cardiovascular
health, autophagy, and the impact that
GLAC has, then check out the full
version of this video that you're
watching. It's part of the Physionic
Insiders. I told you I'd give you
something to skip. At any rate, all of
my work is there. It's a premium
research review with 100 plus
investigations, articles that accompany
all of my videos, shorten summaries, and
if you're looking for reputable sources
for supplements, I have a master
supplement list that includes glycine
and NAC. There's a lot more perks like
these, but I'm talking to myself at this
point, so I'll go ahead and check back
to the material.
Now, back in 2023, I was unaware of
another Glimax study in humans that had
also been released, but the participants
were people with type 2 diabetes. Now, I
won't drag you through the figures, but
oh, by the way, I forgot to mention that
if you're interested in checking out the
Physionic Insiders for my full analysis
on GLAC and more, the link is in the
description. Didn't expect that, did
you? You skipper. Okay, the bottom line
is that diabetes uh study that I'm
talking about is that GLEAC also helped
these individuals substantially. Okay,
I'm bringing this up, sure, for more
evidence in humans, but also because I
stated multiple times that I think GLEAC
only helps select people, two groups of
people to be specific. One, as we saw,
older individuals. Now, I said a
relatively arbitrary cut off of 60 years
old, but it's not like if you're 59, you
have to count down the days for your
birthday before you you're allowed to
take GLIAC.
And two, I predicted that it would help
people who were younger than 60, but
maybe dealing with chronic health
issues. And guess what? This study is
exactly that. These people are in their
early 50s, some even in their 40s. And
it's cool being able to predict
something and then seeing clear evidence
of that prediction being correct. Okay,
so those are the two groups, older
individuals on average and younger
individuals with some form of chronic
health issues. Now, there's a lot of
wiggle room for nuances there, but we
just don't have the data to refine that
right now except for some new dementia
trials. Why not others? Like a person
who's 32 but not dealing with serious
chronic health issues? Well, because if
you think back to this graph, the second
bar there is for younger individuals
supplementing with Gleak. And you can
see that well, nothing happens. Granted,
it's only 2 weeks, but if we use the
same comparison for older folks, there's
a sizable rise in just two weeks. So,
the evidence, though limited, indicates
that Glinac is not worth it for people
who are quite a bit younger. So, here's
how I'd approach it. If I'm around 60 or
older, it might be worth it. Though, I
would have you listen to what I'll be
saying next because there's two
important things to know. If I'm any
age, but dealing with chronic health
issues, though, we don't have specifics,
it might be worthwhile, especially
against uh insulin resistance. Now, if
you're neither of those camps, I
probably wouldn't bother. Now, the dose
used in these studies is staggering.
We're talking 100 mg
per kilogram of weight per day of each.
Those are huge amounts. Now with the
insiders a year or so ago, we did a bit
of math and estimated based on the NAC
specific studies that dose could be
reasonably reduced to 2 g per day total
for each and we should still see
effectiveness. That's much more
manageable, but keep in mind it's a shot
in the dark. As more data releases, I
hope to refine those numbers. Now to the
accept. Here's the thing that I should
mention. There are multiple randomized
control trials on GLIAC. So on the face
of it, that's great news, congruence in
the literature. But the big thing still
holding me back from jumping completely
on board is the fact that every single
RCT, randomized control trial that has
been done has come out of one
laboratory. It's a reputable lab out of
Baylor Medicine. But until I see some of
these results replicated by other labs,
I'm a little hesitant yet. You may not
feel that way, and I think that's
perfectly reasonable response. But
regardless, I think it should be
acknowledged. That said, what's this?
Another video on Quaba. If you want to
learn some more with me, then check it
out. I've heard this one is a good one.
Though, I also have no idea what I'm
going to be linking here yet, so I could
be completely wrong. Maybe I'll add the
supplement routine that I designed for
my dad if you're interested. At any
rate, thanks for tuning in. Catch you in
the next one.